Saulo Moreira Junior SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- saulo.moreira@protonmail.com
- (438) 809-5506
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/saulo-moreira-905372136/
- O https://github.com/saulomoreira1983/
- Montreal, QC

SUMMARY

Driven, organized, detail-oriented problem solver, logical thinker and self-motivated person able to bring many years of work ethic and experience in a variety of challenging fields. Enthusiastic to collaborate with an organization where I can continuously grow as a developer and within the company.

LANGUAGES

English, French and Portuguese

EDUCATION

John Abbott College, Montreal – Internet Programming and Development	2021
Instituto Packter, Porto Alegre (Brazil) - Clinical Philosophy	2012
Federal University of Pernambuco, Recife (Brazil) – Bachelor in Philosophy	2010

TECHNOLOGIES

LANGUAGES: Java, C#, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP

DATABASES: MySql, SQL Server IDE: Visual Studio. NetBeans. VSCode

CODE MANAGEMENT: GitHub, BitBucket, Sourcetree PROJECT MANAGEMENT: Agile, Jira, Trello, Scrum

PROJECTS

PERSONAL BANKING January 2021

Desktop application that allows bank clients to keep track of their bank accounts, view balance, perform transactions, view numerical and graphical spending reports, download or email proofs of transactions, monthly statements and update personal information.

TECHNOLOGIES: C#, SQL Server, Visual Studio, Entity Framework, Azure, MVC, Unit Testing

MANAGEMENT TOOLS: Trello, Scrum

GIT HUB: https://github.com/saulomoreira1983/BankCRM-OnlineBanking

BANK MANAGEMENT SYSTEM December 2020

Desktop application designed for bank branch representatives to manage clients, accounts, perform transactions, issue receipts and generate monthly statements and reports that can be e-mailed or printed.

TECHNOLOGIES: C#, SQL Server, Visual Studio, WPF, Entity Framework

MANAGEMENT TOOLS: Trello, Scrum

GIT HUB: https://github.com/saulomoreira1983/BankCRM-OnlineBanking

THE DOG THERAPISTS WEBSITE October 2020

Responsive website that offers training programs for pets, displays pictures and information about satisfied 'customers' and provides a form in which the user can input personal and pet's information for free assessment.

TECHNOLOGIES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VS Code

FRAMEWORK: Bootstrap 4.5

GIT HUB: https://github.com/saulomoreira1983/The-Dog-Therapists-website

WORK EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS OWNER June 2018 – October 2019

Optimum Inc. (10633593 Canada Inc.) - Recruitment Agency - Canada

- Selected and interviewed candidates
- Organized budget and expenses
- Planned the online platform and the recruitment system
- ${\it \mathbb{L}}$ Responsible for the human relations between the company's partners and the subcontractors
- General administration

TECHNICAL SUPPORT AGENT February 2018 – June 2018

CGI - IT Company - Canada

- Provided technical support to the company's clients across the globe
- Showed high listening skills and emotional intelligence

BILINGUAL CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

August 2014 - October 2017

Finastra - Finance and Technology - Canada

- Answered incoming calls (average 50/day) resolving issues with both branch representatives and end customers
- Interacted with several departments in order to manage the best way to get things done efficiently, demonstrating sense of cooperation and strong abilities as a team-worker
- Consistently scored above 85% on the quality assurance of the company, and often making top-3 with more than 90% in scorecard related to call quality
- Performed always among the bests of cheques department according to statistics related to efficiency, being consistently part of the top-3 stats performer of the company
- Demonstrated an important leadership experience during a crisis due to a logistics issue at the production department, suggesting a new insertion to the script to persuade cancelling customers to stay with the company, resulting in a 5% decrease in delayed orders cancellations
- Made follow up lists to make sure the most complicated cases and certain bank orders placed electronically by branches would be completed successfully, detecting important fixable issues (average 5/week) in production, saving company's money avoiding useless reorders at no charge
- Reached the required level to have the training for the eSwitch role, provided in September 2017 only to the top agents
- # Had excellent feedback from branch representatives and end customers, who often thanked and highlighted the astonishing customer experience and service they had in the emails to the leaders

HIGH SCHOOL TEACHER - Philosophy

January 2010 - January 2012

Espaço Educacional Alternativo - Education - Brazil

- Prepared own materials and texts
- Helped students individually with more difficulty to learn the main subjects
- Zaught extra-curricular courses in subjects like Logic, Ethics and Aesthetics
- Encouraged students to think by themselves, with an epistemological and rational view of the world

EXECUTIVE SUPERVISOR 2001 – 2009

Amoreira Ltd. - Commerce - Brazil

- Megotiated a costs savings plan with distributors that cut business expenses by R\$12,000 (approximately C\$ 4,600) annually
- Negotiated a deal to be the exclusive seller of a baby furniture brand in the city of Recife, which allowed our company to be competitive even with a net profit of more than 50% commercializing their products
- ${\it L}$ Created a rewarding program for the sellers, increasing overall sales by more than 10%
- Promoted training for the sales team (9 people), developing and creating creative sales techniques, that generated R\$16,200 (approximately C\$6,320) yearly in additional revenue
- Managed administrative and financial tasks, including an all-new logistics program (delivery and assembly), which pushed up our customers' satisfaction pool by 23%

CONTINUING EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

Certificate in Networking – Cisco	2017
Google Apps Administrator Fundamentals – Google	2015
Certificate in Parapsychology – CLAP (Latin American Centre of Parapsychology)	2012
Entrepreneurship Course - Sebrae	2004

VOLUNTEERING

FUNDRAISER - Dublin, Ireland

December 2013 - April 2014

 $\label{to raise funds to the Irish Heart Foundation and Red Cross \\$

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Technology, cinema, soccer, philosophy, poetry, science, economy, knowledge of diverse cultures